#### MICHAEL D. SHEROKEE

9394 Doral Dr. Warren, OH 44484

michael.sherokee@gmail.com

cell: 330-301-5509 home: 330-856-6762

## **Summary**

Over 25 years of experience as writer, proofreader, and professional translator/instructor of Italian and French culture. Additional experience as team lead for instructors in various roles as an educator. Highly experienced in working in teams, both remotely and in person. Currently a new graduate of Full Stack Web Development at NuCamp and fulfilling the role of Remote AI Language Specialist collaborating with other language professionals and AI Engineers.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

**Linguistic Collaborator/Proofreader and Translator (Present-Part time)** The Language Doctors Inc./Polilingua LLC/ACE Global – Translation and Machine Post-Editing/Cultural Mediation (Spanish, French, Italian)

Generative AI Language Specialist/QA Auditor – Innodata Inc. (Remote) Cultural Mediation and AI Response Enhancement Specialization (JavaScript, Python, API localization, Mongo DB, React/React Native Development)

**Business Developer (Present-Part time)-** HSC Global. Business Communications on Import and Export in China and abroad. Creation of Online Content to promote Marketing Sales in International Markets.

**Educator Italian/French** (Fall 2012- Fall 2020)- Naples American High School. Dodds Europe. Department of Defense Education Activity. Grades 7-12.

**Educator Italian/French (Summer/Fall 2011-Summer 2012)**- New Castle Area School District. New Castle, PA. Director/Instructor Italian Language Program, Grades 6-12. Instructor French Program Grade 6.

**Permanent Substitute Instructor of Italian (Spring-Summer 2011)**- New Castle Area School District New Castle, PA.

Permanent Substitute Instructor of Spanish/French (Winter-Spring 2011)- Hubbard High School, Hubbard, Ohio.

Coordinator of Foreign Language Assistants and Assistant to tutors (ESL)- Luca Pacioli Institute of Modern Languages Crema, Italy (2008-09)

Native English Instructor/Collaborator with Italian Teachers (ESL)- Luca Pacioli Institute of Modern Languages Crema, Italy (2007-08)

Business Assistant-marketing, Instructor and Interpreter English/Italian-Whirpool Europe. Sede di Casinetta di Biandronno, Casinetta, (Spring 2008).

**Business Consultant/ Assistant, Instructor and Interpreter English/Italian-**Huntsman (Italy) Srl. Sede di Ternate, (Spring 2008).

## Writing Advisor, The Ohio State University (2005-07)

Tutor in writing in beginning Italian Writing Workshops (undergraduates only); 2006-07 Multiple Topics

### **EDUCATION**

Intensive Masters in Conference Interpretation and Negotiation, SSIT - Scuola Superiore per Interpreti e Traduttori - Pescara (Summer 2023)

# Master of Arts in Italian Summa cum laude, The Ohio State University (June, 2007)

Thesis: « *L'orang-utang e la dolce pantera* »: Le lettere amorose di Giosuè Carducci a Carolina Cristofori Piva. Director: Prof. Charles Klopp

# Bachelor of Arts and Sciences in Italian/French *Magna cum laude*, Youngstown State University (2003)

Thesis: « La dimostrazione dell'intelligenza in tre novelle del Decamerone».

Director: Prof. Iole Checcone

**Bachelor of Science in Education, Youngstown State University (Fall 2010)** 

### **PUBLICATIONS**

« La dimostrazione dell'intelligenza in tre novelle del Decamerone». Youngstown State University. (Dec. 2003).

« *L'orang-utang e la dolce pantera* »: Le lettere amorose di Giosuè Carducci a Carolina Cristoferi Piva. The Ohio State University. (June, 2007).

## **ACADEMIC SERVICE**

**Department Chair, Department of World Languages** - Naples Middle High School 2014-16 Coordination of meetings, teacher trainings, Curriculum decision making, School Administration and Collaboration, Organizational and Alignment Strategic Planning, Virtual Collaboration for World Language Teachers - Europe and Pacific, etc.

**Assistant at Conference** « Borders Culture and The Construction of Identity: The Case of Trieste». October 2006

**Assistant Coordinator** at the 12th Annual French and Italian Graduate Students Association (FIGSA) Conference: "Storytelling, Gender Studies and Cultural Citizenship: French and Italian Discussions on Identity," April 2006

### LANGUAGES

English: native speaker Italian: near-native speaker French: near-native speaker Spanish: near-native speaker Turkish: elementary level Chinese: elementary level

## REFERENCES

Patricia Salerno, 4th Grade Partial Language Immersion Teacher Patricia.Salerno@eu.dodea.edu
Vicenza Elementary School +(39)0456039210
0444-717710 Vicenza, Italy

Mrs. Maddalena Amero, Director/Instructor Foreign Languages Program m.amero@boardman Boardman High School, Department of Foreign Languages schools.org 7777 Glenwood Ave. Boardman, OH 44512 (330) 261-5911

**Dr. Charles Klopp, Professor**/Director of Graduate Studies in Italian klopp.2@osu.edu The Ohio State University, Department of French and Italian (614) 292-7585 1775 College Road – Hagerty Hall 200. Columbus, OH 43210